Mick P. Duffy

Full Stack Web Developer

302.753.6317 mick@mduffy.dev www.linkedin.com/in/mick-duffy www.mduffy.dev

Creative problem solver and systems thinker with a serious passion for this work. With the ability to adapt swiftly to complex challenges and a readiness to learn, I bring my passion for coding together with strong analytical capacities and over 10 years' experience in tech to get the job done.

Service-oriented and **tenacious**. Highly **collaborative** and **resourceful**. An **eager** learner and **industrious** self-starter with a positive attitude.

Experience with **multiple databases and programming languages**, and a **lifelong** love of all things tech.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

IT Manager, Tech Generalist

The Curran Firm P.C. Media, PA | 2017-Present

Fulfilling the complex technical needs of a leading law firm in Greater Philadelphia and collaborating with principals, staff attorneys, and clients on various technological challenges and case-related issues

- Providing instant tech support to attorneys, support staff, clients, and experts
- Maintenance of computer hardware, software, and peripheral devices
- Maintenance of all client records (paper and digital)
- E-filing important court documents and streamlining of technological and administrative processes

Trial Technologist, Court Videographer

Self-Employed Philadelphia, PA | 2012-Present

Developed a powerful, lower-cost alternative to traditional courtroom documentation technologies, offering multimedia presentation of video clips, documents, photographs, and records that enhance the records-keeping process and mitigate challenges in the high-stress environment of the courtroom

- Setting up a plan according to the physical layout of the courtroom to make sure the presentation will have the maximum impact on the jury
- Working in partnership with a team of attorneys in a variety of civil legal matters
- Helping secure several multi-million-dollar verdicts for clients in high-profile cases
- Multimedia recordings of depositions for the court and jury playbacks

First-Party Quality Assurance Tester

Sony Computer Entertainment of America (SCEA) San Diego, CA | 2006-2008

Hired to provide expert testing, QA, and continuous improvement support for a team of developers and designers behind an array of Sony products including NBA2K, WarHawk, ATV Off-Road Fury, and Heavenly Sword

- Identifying, replicating, and communicating a variety of videogame bugs and glitches to the programming development staff
- Testing and debugging of online and networking features of several games

SELECTED PROJECTS

FireStorm

A classic side-scrolling platform game that employs JavaScript, MongoDB, React, Phaser 3, Passport.js, and Express. Developed by a four-person team in a three-week period.

The Beer Genie & the Pairing Pickle

A web application that searches a beer API to find an optimal selection based on the style that the user chooses. The Beer Genie then consults a recipe API to find recipes that pair well with the beer choice of the user (the Pairing Pickle).

SKILLS

HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, MongoDB, Node.JS, React, mySQL, express, Firebase, Ajax, Sequelize, Prototyping, User Testing, Mobile and Responsive Design

Microsoft Office; Adobe Creative Suite (Acrobat, InDesign, InCopy, Photoshop, Premiere Pro), Trial Director, TimeCoder Pro

EDUCATION

University of Pennsylvania: College of Liberal & Professional Studies (Philadelphia, PA) Intensive Coding Bootcamp

Completed May 2019, 'A' average